so I've been making videos recently
about um you know Project based learning
and real learning and um this video is
one of many in sort of a segment about
learning what's required for your career
and how to learn it and I've been you
know putting the kibos on a lot of these
for Education uh Alternatives out there
and a very relevant question came up
what about hack the Box what about try
hack me what about uh the kubernetes
equivalent I forget the name of it het
Tannis uses that all the time I love it
and the answer is somewhat the same for
all of them but more particularly true
for hack the box and try hack me okay um
so and and you're right you're asking
about so so there's actually three
different careers that are involved in
that question so let's break it down I
got my hoodie on so we'll talk about the
cyber security profession and what that
involves and
if hack the boxes try hack me which are
specifically for cyber security what are
they are they good right um and it's
super important because I mean the
beginning of this entire segment that
includes this video and several others
is learning the right you know finding
the right learning resources for the
career that you have targeted I'm going
to say it again please please please
watch the video about targeting your
career before you launch down the path
of learning or you'll do like I did I I
sign up for hack the box I I I did the
twitch thing I was convinced I was going
to get my ocp and then I found out what
it actually meant to be I did a video
about this what it actually meant to be
a cyber security expert which is mostly
reports 50% at least and I was like damn
I don't want to do that and I changed so
please make sure you understand that
cyber security is the path for you
before you commit to something like hack
the box and try hack me so having said
that
disclaimer yet
um that I want to talk about that only
right so the question about devops and
and and kubernetes and up those are
those are not cyber security okay they
are Administration and operations sorts
of things I believe quite quickly in
spoiler alert can be more better learned
by building your own lab building your
own kubon lab back here is better right
but can you do hack the Box types of
things and try hack me things on your
own lab not as well okay so again we're
talking about several careers here and I
want to disambiguate them up front so
that you know when I talk about hack the
boxes try hack me I'm talking very
specifically extremely specifically
about cyber security cyber security is
one of those only things where you
cannot learn it really uh without having
something to
hack so
I mean honestly right you've got to
create something to hack
now and most of the time when you're
talking about having something to hack
if you in the old days before hack the
box and try hack me existed you know old
school hackers like me and believe me my
skills are nowhere near anybody lately I
mean yeah you know most of the that you
would have to create a system that had
the vulnerabilities which is really fun
by the way it actually is really fun so
the the short answer is yes hack the box
and try hack me are worth the money
they're worth the
investment uh we're making a video right
now I'll answer the Linux Jedi question
in a second so um the answer is I
specifically hack the Box uh there are
videos If you go search up my YouTube of
me doing try hackme and so in order to
be a hacker on hack the box and try
hackme they created these um these these
programs there's there's like a track
for learning Linux it's absolutely at
least when I did it I did to try hack me
like segment on Linux it's abysmally bad
and it demonstrates a fundamental lack
of understanding the Unix operating
system and the philosophy in general in
fact some of the errors were so
glaringly bad that it was it became
comical and you can probably go dig up
my YouTube one of my thousands of
YouTube videos someplace in there is me
doing tryck me um there's over the wire
which is also learning about Linux and
stuff and hacking and hack the box and
it's fun and all but it's not like
you're going to get a job doing it one
of the reasons that I
actually have to put hack the box and
and to some degree as well to try hack
me but especially hack the box into the
category of valuable worth the money
learning is because they not only do
they provide a number of real systems
that you actually hack using a VPN
remember that whole thing about being
real the systems and try hack me and
hack the Box are actual systems they
might be containerized doesn't matter
they are actual systems the things that
you do when you hack against a system on
hack the Box are exactly the same things
that you would do otherwise this is not
the same as fre code camp for webdb or
code academy for webd or some gamified
crap out there that's helping you learn
a thing without doing the thing this is
the thing right so when you hack the Box
you are literally hacking the box a box
you're they're setting a box up with the
B abilities for you they're doing the
kind of thing that you would have done
for yourself which is to set up a box
and put a bunch of vulnerabilities on it
and and then you're and the thing is so
cool about hack the box and to be fair I
don't have anything to do with them uh I
still have a professional hack the box
subscription which I paid in advance for
even though I don't use it that much
because I'm spending too much time
making these and doing bike videos um
but but but yeah there's there's um in
fact it used to be that hack the Box uh
you couldn't even get on unless you
hacked you had to hack in to get an
account and they changed all that um but
it is tremendously valuable um to use
something like hack the Box um there's
and so the answer there is I actually
think it's phenomenally awesome the
reason I think hack the box is awesome
is because it is not in the category of
for Education crap that's you know not
the real thing it's the real thing and
in order to hack it you have to install
the tools to do that whether the tools
are Cali or you you set up your own ARS
dist and put your own stuff in there or
you're using parrot or or you know
you're you're gent toing your own way
into you know hacker happiness you are
using real tools and you're hacking real
systems and in order to hack any system
these days pretty much almost all of the
hacking involves you know a network
connection so having the boxes be on the
internet someplace over a VPN virtual
private Network which you need to really
fundamentally understand if you're going
to be a hacker every single skill down
to setting up the VPN and getting it to
work and installing all the tools onto
your own system to do the hacking every
single one of those skills is real that
is the short answer that is the reason
that hack the box is a very very good
thing it's my favorite of all of them by
the way far far more uh uh robust than
try hack me in my opinion I haven't done
trackme to be fair in two years at least
um and and again so so that's the answer
um if you are doing hack the box there
is a kind of a follow-up question to
this and I'm just going to lump it into
here somebody asked about Capture the
Flag games um there are a number of
Capture the Flag sites um and
opportunities out there you got to kind
of Define what capture the flag is um if
capture the flag is going into bringing
your tools your real tools I mean you
know the answer here right if you bring
real tools to a hack Capture the Flag
competition and you use those tools to
to to capture the flag and win then yeah
it's a great thing if it's too contrived
though like seriously like I remember
Carnegie melan put um on one of their
things they they had this like they they
put this this really horrible
um uh uh I want to I can't remember the
name of it they they this really
horrible like frontend game engine uh on
the front of their their was was
targeted at at Junior and and high
school kids and they put this like
really horrible like gamified front end
on the hacking part of it and to try to
motivate people to use it and it was
just disastrously bad it just distracted
from the whole thing so I want to be
really careful here if you're doing a
capture of the flag and they put
themselves under Capture the Flag
officially um and and so so yeah that's
how you know it's real or not right so
Educators unfortunately um they tend to
like to make things fun I think the best
the the in terms of making it fun is
still useful and real the best you can
really do we used to have a competition
at skill stack um it wasn't really
hacking what I told everybody I said
okay everybody you you all need to add
uh an account to your system you had to
add a Unix account to your system that
has uh the following you know password
to it and I forced them all to make
their their machines vulnerable
temporarily and then we had a
competition to see if you can keep the
other person out of your box how can you
shut down their processes when they make
a connection how can you write uh a
shell script Loop to keep them out how
can you notice when they when they've
attacked you how can you sneak a back
door in before they catch you and all
this stuff and it was really fun and it
was all very very real and then we
rolled back the systems and took the
accounts off the system that qualified
as sort of a capture the flag kind of
you know hacker competition it was
tremendously fun we would put the you
know the hacker music
on and we would just go to town having
fun hacking each other with hack the you
know and hack the box kind of away
except for it was like us versus another
so hack the box is a really great thing
again I have nothing to do with them uh
if if the hack the Box people happen to
come across this video a good job it's
been a long time since I've done any of
your of your stuff and maybe someday
I'll start when I when I get back into
it but if you're going specifically if
you're going into cyber security do hack
the box if you're not it's not worth
your time seriously if you're going to
go into operations or devops or software
development or webdb or any of these
other amazing techer or AI or machine
learning and think God hack the box is
completely irrelevant this is only
relevant specifically and by the way I
would give hack the box your money
before I gave something like offensive
security your money offensive security
is an amazing tool as well I'll do a
separate video about that completely um
if you're going to go into cyber
security specifically so that's the
answer about that